【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 23]
[第23集]
Why do you think bandits have anything to do with me?
你凭什么认为土匪 跟我有什么关系？
Someone ambushed you on the hunting grounds.
有人在狩猎场伏击了你。
This never happened.
这从未发生过。
Does it also have something to do with me?
是不是也跟我有关系呢？
You know everyone in this palace, except Wang Dequan,
这宫里的人你都认识， 除了王德全，
He is an old servant of the former emperor.
是前任皇帝的老仆人。
The rest is all brought by you.
剩下的全都是你带来的。
How did I pull them off?
我是怎么把他们拉下来的
No one knows?
没有人知道吗？
What about military tokens?
军事令牌呢？
since you became regent
自从你成为摄政王以来
The He family was wiped out.
何家被灭门，
The Yan family was sent to Sichuan
严家被发配到四川
After the hunt.
狩猎之后。
Which of them doesn't want it?
他们谁不想要呢？
Why do you think it's me?
为什么你认为是我？
You are my uncle.
你是我叔叔。
Your Majesty, there is no need to quibble.
陛下，无需狡辩。
But you should know about the He family.
但何家的事你应该知道。
I'm more concerned about
我更关心的是
These are dangerous and unpredictable situations.
这些危险且不可预测的情况。
Do you admit it?
你承认吗
Did you frame the entire He family?
整个何家都是你陷害的？
Your Majesty has been in poor health recently.
陛下最近身体不太好。
Rest in the palace from now on.
从此以后就在皇宫里休息吧。
You don't need to worry about anything else.
您无需担心其他事情。
Do you want to put me under house arrest?
你想软禁我吗？
No.
不。
I just
我只是
Try sharing your concerns.
尝试分享您的担忧。
How...how dare you?
你怎么……你怎么敢？
guard!
卫兵！
Where are the guards?
守卫在哪里？
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
Your Majesty,
陛下，
Do you know how to curse now?
你现在知道怎么骂人了吗？
I'm too kind.
我太善良了。
I convinced the bird that it had strong wings.
我让这只鸟相信它有坚强的翅膀。
Since you think you are an eagle, I will put you in a cage
既然你以为自己是鹰， 那我就把你关在笼子里
so you know
所以你知道
You are just a caged bird.
你只是一只笼中鸟。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
You said I'm not the person you're destined to be
你说我不是你命中注定的人
And I am not on your marriage line.
而且我不在你的婚姻线上。
So why no matter how we wander
那么为什么无论 我们如何流浪
Even if we are thousands of miles apart,
即使我们相隔千里，
I still married you
我还是嫁给了你
And fell in love with you?
并爱上了你？
Isn't this fate?
这不是命运吗？
I can't imagine that future
我无法想象那样的未来
With anyone but you.
与除了你之外的任何人。
Just be a general.
当将军就好了。
The future General Rong.
未来的荣将军。
Your General Xiaorong.
你的小荣将军。
What if she was a girl?
如果她是个女孩怎么办？
We will pamper her to no end.
我们会无休无止地宠她。
Not to mention ten years, not even a day,
别说十年，连一天也没有，
Do we want her to leave us and go to Mount Wuhua to suffer?
难道我们要让她离开我们去五华山受苦吗？
Thinking of our General Xiaorong or Miss Xiaorong
想着我们的小容将军 或者小容小姐
Let my heart sing.
让我的心歌唱。
Usually, it's you who runs to me.
通常，是你跑向我。
Can I finally contact you this time?
这次我终于可以 联系到你了吗？
Normally, I don't give people second chances.
通常，我不会 给人第二次机会。
But for you, I am willing to give countless opportunities.
但为了你， 我愿意给予无数的机会。
I've run to you.
我已经跑到你身边了。
if you still love me
如果你还爱我的话
Just stretch out your hand,
只要伸出你的手，
I am willing to give you all my love
我愿意给你我全部的爱
And sincerity for the rest of my life.
和我余生的真诚。
What if I told you
如果我告诉你怎么办
I do not like you anymore?
我不喜欢你了？
Then why did you rush into the fire to save me?
那你为什么要冲进火里救我？
The fire was so intense.
火势如此猛烈。
I can't even escape myself.
我连自己都无法逃脱。
Why did you do that?
你为什么要那么做？
I will save anyone without hesitation
我会毫不犹豫地拯救任何人
Inside the Astrology Hall.
占星馆内。
I can't stand idly by
我不能袖手旁观
And watching someone die in front of me.
并看着某人死在我面前。
but…
但…
Since you are so upright and noble,
既然你如此正直、高尚，
why are you going to all this trouble
你为什么要这么麻烦
Eliminate everyone who is harmful to me?
消灭所有对我有害的人？
All I did was help the emperor
我所做的只是为了帮助皇帝
Destroy the bad guys as quickly as possible.
以最快的速度消灭坏人。
I didn't think too much about it.
我没有考虑太多。
School is out! School is out!
学校放学了！学校放学了！
Master, I want to pray for Xingxiang Pavilion tonight.
师父，今晚我要为 星象阁祈福。
Can you tell me what to say?
你能告诉我该说什么吗？
OK Go play.
好的。去玩。
Thank you Master.
谢谢师父。
let's go. Let's go play together.
我们走吧。我们一起去玩吧。
OK
好的。
When I'm sick and confused,
当我生病、迷茫时，
I only recognized you.
我只认出了你。
That will definitely give you false hope,
那一定会给你虚假的希望，
But this is just an illusion.
但这只是幻觉。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
why do you think
为什么你认为
i will still love you
我仍然会爱你
After knowing that you burned down my Xingxiang Pavilion?
知道你烧了我星象阁之后？
Did Madam run to put out the fire?
夫人是跑去救火吧？
that's right.
这是正确的。
correct?
正确的？
Your Highness, the Emperor is not having an easy time right now.
殿下， 现在皇上的日子不太好过。
As Jialin’s mainstay,
作为嘉琳的中流砥柱，
Please give me more guidance in the future.
今后请给我更多的指导。
please.
请。
——Master, the young master is back! - This is…
——主人，少主回来了！ - 这是…
minute.
分钟。
Father.
父亲。
what happened?
发生了什么？
Master Rong said I won’t see you again.
容大师说不会再见你了。
All these things are yours.
所有这些东西都是你的。
You can take them away.
你可以把它们带走。
If you don't want them, I'll have them thrown away.
如果你不想要它们， 我会让人把它们扔掉。
Zhanping.
Zhanping.
I -
我 -
Stop talking.
别说话了。
I don't know how to face you now.
我现在不知道该如何面对你。
Teacher Rong is so kind to you.
荣老师对你真好。
Why do you want to hurt him like this?
你为什么要这样伤害他？
If you are going through something, you can tell us.
如果您正在经历某些事情， 可以告诉我们。
Do you know how important Xingxiang Pavilion is to him?
你知道 星象阁对于他来说有多重要吗？
forget it.
忘了它。
This is the money Master Rong has prepared for you. You should leave.
这是容师傅给你准备的钱。 你应该离开。
No.
不。
Does he have any other news for me?
他还有其他消息给我吗？
nothing.
没什么。
You should leave. If you don't, I'll have to kick you out.
你应该离开。 如果你不这样做，我就得把你赶走。
Stop pretending. It doesn't work.
别再假装了。它不起作用。
Master Rong and I will never trust you again.
我和容大师再也不会相信你了。
I understand.
我懂了。
Then tell him to take care.
然后告诉他要保重。
I won't bother him anymore.
我不会再打扰他了。
Don't say these hypocritical things.
别说这些虚伪的话。
You are the worst person ever. Let's go.
你是有史以来最糟糕的人。走吧。
Xunxunan humiliates us like this.
寻寻南这样羞辱我们。
My sister is still waiting for us to rescue her.
我姐姐还在等我们来救她。
Father, please raise an army.
父亲，请起兵吧。
nonsense!
废话！
How could you start a war so hastily?
怎能如此贸然发动战争？
This is a blatant provocation.
这是公然的挑衅。
Should we just let Ren Yinxiao be rude?
难道就任由任寅晓无礼吗？
Do you want your sister to die in a foreign country?
难道要让妹妹死在异国他乡吗？
when i leave,
当我离开时，
My sister is still locked in that useless prince's yard.
我的妹妹还被锁在 那个没用的王子的院子里。
She couldn't even get a decent meal.
她连一顿像样的饭都吃不上。
If we don't act quickly,
如果我们不赶快采取行动，
We may have to collect her body, father.
我们可能得去收集她的尸体，父亲。
I…
我…
I wrote a letter to Ren Yinxiao.
我给任寅晓写封信。
What good does this letter do?
这封信有什么好处呢？
It was obvious they were not afraid of us.
很明显他们不怕我们。
Otherwise, they would not make such a move.
不然的话，他们也不会做出这样的举动。
Do you know what conscription means?
你知道征兵意味着什么吗？
Do you know what preparations are needed for war?
你知道 打仗需要做什么准备吗？
War is a conflict between two sides
战争是双方的冲突
We can't just jump in just because of one person.
我们不能 因为一个人就一头扎进去。
But - but she's your daughter.
但是——但是她是你的女儿。
She is also my sister.
她也是我的妹妹。
She was given the title of princess.
她被授予公主的称号。
She now represents Jia Lin.
她现在代表家琳。
what do you know
你知道些什么
Diplomatic and court affairs?
外交和法庭事务？
you are right.
你是对的。
i don't know anything about it
我对此一无所知
But I know you're afraid.
但我知道你害怕。
before you do anything,
在你做任何事情之前，
You always go to Xingxiang Pavilion to ask Rong Gong.
你总是去星象阁 问容公。
You are always cautious, timid, and careful.
你总是小心翼翼、胆怯、小心翼翼。
How can you achieve something significant?
你怎样才能取得重大成就？
you…
你…
anything else?
还要别的吗？
This is enough.
这就够了。
OK
好的。
Are you blind?
你是瞎子吗？
Now you even dare to bully me?
现在连你都敢欺负我了？
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
what happened?
发生了什么？
You don't hate me now.
你现在不恨我了。
I do.
我愿意。
It's just that I'm not in the mood right now.
只是我现在没心情。
He Jiuling,
He Jiuling,
I have something to tell you.
我有件事要告诉你。
I don't believe a word you said.
你说的我一个字都不信。
King Xunnan is not that kind of person.
寻南王不是那样的人。
How do you know he's not like that?
你怎么知道他不是那样的人？
If you slander others again
如果你再诽谤别人
I'll teach you a lesson.
我会给你一个教训。
I just remembered...
我刚想起来……
gentlemen.
先生。
You two are old acquaintances, aren't you?
你们两个是老熟人了，不是吗？
When I was still Prince Yong,
当年还是雍亲王的时候，
He even proposed in the palace.
他甚至在宫殿里求婚。
Although he failed to marry you,
虽然他没能娶你，
You two are at least friends.
你们两个至少是朋友。
He is really lucky.
他真的很幸运。
He Jiuling,
He Jiuling,
Now there is no one to help my sister.
现在没有人可以帮助我妹妹了。
can you help me if possible
如果可以的话你能帮我吗
To save my sister?
为了救我妹妹？
Sit here and make tea for you
坐在这里为你泡茶
It was through gnashing of teeth.
是通过咬牙切齿的。
How dare you embarrass Miss He?
竟敢为难何小姐？
Here you go, sir.
给你，先生。
- sorry. - please.
- 对不起。 - 请。
Before, my sister and I
以前，我和姐姐
Did a lot of bad things to you.
对你做了很多坏事。
I always feel sorry.
我总是感到遗憾。
I sincerely apologize and will do my best
我真诚地道歉并会尽一切努力
To make it up to you.
来弥补你。
Apologize?
道歉？
Do you really think apologizing can solve everything?
你真以为道歉 就能解决一切吗？
Stop pretending you don't know what's going on here.
别再假装你不知道 这里发生了什么事。
Tan.
谭。
I can write to you to ask about the situation,
我可以写信 给你询问情况，
But there is nothing I can do.
但我无能为力。
even so,
即便如此，
You are the only one who can help me.
你是唯一能帮助我的人。
My apology just now was sincere.
我刚才的道歉是真诚的
From the bottom of my heart.
我从心底里。
If you need my help in the future
如果你以后需要我的帮助
with anything,
与任何事物，
Even help you reverse the case,
甚至帮你翻案，
You can come to me anytime.
你可以随时来找我。
unnecessary.
不需要。
No.
不。
I will always remember this in my heart.
我会把这件事永远记在心里。
You and Rong Yu are
你和容宇是
Much like now.
现在很像。
If it were you before
如果是以前的你
You would have laughed before
以前你一定会笑
And scolded me
还骂我
For those in this situation,
对于处于这种情况，
but now you want
但现在你愿意
sit with people you don't like
和你不喜欢的人坐在一起
Even invited me to tea.
甚至请我喝茶。
Although I hate to admit it,
虽然我很不愿意承认，
You and Rong Yu are actually a good match.
你和容羽其实很般配。
What a fool.
真是个蠢才。
Do you intentionally make others angry?
你是故意让别人生气吗？
Jiuling, let’s go.
九龄，我们走吧。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
Can I…
我可以吗…
can i be your friend?
我可以成为你的朋友吗？
We will never be friends.
我们永远不会成为朋友。
go out! You all go out.
出去！你们都出去吧。
Cheng'an, it's me.
成安，是我。
Cheng'an.
Cheng'an.
elder sister.
姐姐。
I know you'll be fine.
我知道你会没事的。
Cheng'an, I'm not just good at
承安，我不只是擅长
Pray to Bodhisattva for help.
祈求菩萨帮助。
Believe me.
相信我。
In times of crisis,
在危机时刻，
I can protect you too.
我也可以保护你。
[Jiang's Mansion]
[Jiang's Mansion]
You lied to me, right?
你骗了我，对吗？
Things about the He family,
何家的事情，
It has nothing to do with our family, right?
和我们家没有关系吧？
Otherwise, how could I not know anything?
不然我怎么会什么都不知道呢？
For such things,
对于这样的事情，
Do I need to tell you loud and clear?
我需要大声而清楚地告诉你吗？
What now?
现在怎么样？
Why are you telling me all this now?
你为什么现在告诉我这一切？
if you don't want me to know
如果你不想让我知道的话
Why can't you hide it from me forever?
你为什么不能永远瞒着我呢？
Because in the future,
因为在未来，
person sitting on the throne
坐在宝座上的人
It will be you.
将会是你。
How could you say such rebellious words?
怎么能说出这么叛逆的话呢？
Isn't your current position strong enough?
你现在的地位还不够强大吗？
Min, this is not a question of whether it is enough.
敏，这不是 够不够的问题。
If I hadn’t gotten rid of the Nanjiang He family back then,
如果当年我没有除掉南江何家，
Will our family still have its current status?
我们家还会有现在的地位吗？
If I don't stand at the highest position now,
如果我现在不站在最高的位置，
Is there any way out for our family?
我们一家人还有出路吗？
Min, it's time for you to know.
敏，是时候让你知道了。
I don't want to hear these words from you.
我不想听你说这些话。
I only know that when the He family is here,
我只知道何家人在的时候，
Our lives are just as beautiful.
我们的生活也同样美好。
Why do you have to reach such great heights?
为什么你必须达到这么高的高度？
What now?
现在呢？
Shouldn't the most important thing now be to rescue my sister?
现在最重要的事情不是 应该是救出妹妹吗？
My sister is still waiting for us to rescue her.
我姐姐还在等我们来救她。
Now is the moment of truth.
现在是关键时刻。
I won't allow anyone or anything to ruin my plans.
我不会允许任何人或任何事 破坏我的计划。
Not even your sister.
连你妹妹也不行。
So, you mean
那么，你是说
You only care about your future and goals,
你只关心你的未来和目标，
You and my sister get along very well
你和我妹妹相处得很好
Being bullied and self-destructing in Xunnan?
被人欺负，在寻南自毁？
After a while, I'll figure it out.
过一段时间，我就会想办法。
So do you really want to do this?
那么你真的要这么做吗？
I can not believe it,
我不敢相信，
At this time, my closest family members are actually
这个时候，我最亲近的家人其实是
More indifferent than the people I’ve hurt?
比我伤害过的人还冷漠吗？
Stop there.
停在那儿。
Do you think I don't worry or care about Lin?
你以为我不担心、不关心林吗？
There is no turning back.
已经没有回头路了。
Min, you don't want to destroy our whole family, do you?
敏，你不想毁掉我们整个家庭 吧？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
I do not know anything.
我什么都不知道。
I just wish you hadn't told me all this today.
我只是希望你今天没有告诉我这一切。
- minute. - Stop pushing me, Father.
- 分钟。 - 别再逼我了，父亲。
a stranger.
一个陌生人。
Princess of Zealand.
西兰公主。
General He.
何将军。
Lord Jiuling.
Lord Jiuling.
【Guozi Studies】
【国子学】
——He Jiuling. - Your Majesty.
——何九龄。 - 陛下。
hurry up. We may be discovered soon.
赶快。我们可能很快就会被发现。
Jiuling, I…
Jiuling, I…
assassin!
刺客！
You go first, I'll stay behind. go!
你们先走，我留在后面。去！
- go. - There are assassins!
- 去。 - 有刺客！
Master Rong.
荣师傅。
Zhanping.
Zhanping.
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Prepare your horses to fight against General Yan.
备马准备迎战严将军。
Let go of the emperor!
放开皇帝！
You all go!
你们都走吧！
He-He Jiuling.
He-He Jiuling.
move.
移动。
Has it always been you?
难道一直都是你吗？
The palace was crowded with our people.
皇宫里挤满了我们的人。
There is no way you can escape.
你是不可能逃脱的。
You are asking for death.
你这是在自寻死路。
We'll wait and see
我们拭目以待
Who will bear the consequences.
谁将承担后果。
He Jiuling, you'll die.
He Jiuling, you'll die.
Rebellious.
反叛。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
How dare you traitors kidnap His Majesty.
你们这些叛徒竟敢绑架陛下。
He Jiuling asked them to put down their weapons quickly.
贺九龄，让他们赶紧放下 武器。
I will beg my father to spare your life.
我会求我父亲饶你一命。
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
Your Majesty,
陛下，
We need to wait.
我们需要等待。
He Jiuling, I beg you.
何九菱，我求你了。
Are you still insisting?
你还在坚持吗？
Kill them all.
杀光他们。
- stop. - No.
- 停止。 - 不。
His Majesty is still among them.
陛下仍在其中。
shooting.
射击。
stop. Everyone stop.
停止。大家停下来。
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
About the He family,
关于何家，
I asked my father.
我问过我父亲。
I'm very sorry.
我很抱歉。
I can't do anything for you.
我不能为你做任何事。
I…
我…
If I…
如果我…
I knew it very early,
很早就知道，
I would have stopped my father.
我会阻止我父亲的。
If this had never happened,
如果这件事从未发生过，
we can…
我们能…
Can we be friends?
我们可以成为朋友吗？
You'd better not tell me the answer.
你最好不要告诉我答案。
Because next time,
因为下次，
I will definitely do better
我一定会做得更好
Compare…
比…
Master Biron,
比荣师傅，
or even better
甚至更好
than anyone else.
比任何人。
He Jiuling,
He Jiuling,
I like you.
我喜欢你。
minute.
分钟。
Lord Zhongyong. Lord Zhongyong.
Lord Zhongyong. Lord Zhongyong.
Chengyuan three years
成元三年
Jiang Hesen, the loyal Lord of Yong, created chaos in the palace and attempted to murder the emperor.
忠雍君姜和森在宫中制造混乱 ，图谋害皇帝。
Now arrest his accomplices. Minister of Justice Wang Tongren.
现在逮捕他的同伙。 司法部部长王同仁。
Li Mu, Minister of Rites.
礼部侍郎李牧。
Imperial Academy Scholars Zhao Zhen and Jiang Shengtian.
Imperial Academy Scholar Zhao Zhen and Jiang Shengtian.
Those who disobey will be summarily executed.
不服从者 将被立即处决。
By order of the emperor, Jiang Hesen was deprived of his title...
奉皇命， 剥夺江和森的爵位……
minute.
分钟。
He will be executed at Liudaokou at noon
中午在六道口处决他
Give everyone a warning and an example.
给大家以警示 和榜样。
Investigation reveals General He Liang
调查揭露 大将军何梁
He was framed by a traitor for colluding with the enemy.
因勾结敌案而被奸人陷害。
Now restored to the position of General He Liang
现已恢复何梁将军之位
And was awarded the lofty title of Protector of the Country.
并授予护国公的崇高称号。
Now I only have one thing to ask for, the Emperor's favor.
现在我只有一件事请求 皇上的恩惠
what is it?
它是什么？
Can my merits offset the past mistakes of Jiang Rong and Xingxiang Pavilion?
我的功德能抵消姜蓉和星象阁过去的错误吗？
He Chenzhou was reinstated as military supervisor.
恢复何辰洲 军事监察职务。
His wife was given the title of second-class lady and a title of nobility.
赐其夫人为二品夫人， 赐爵位。
[The Tomb of General He Liang] He Qingxing was restored as the internal general.
【何亮大将军之墓】 恢复何庆兴为内将军。
His wife was given the title of third-grade lady and a title of nobility.
赐其夫人为三品夫人， 赐爵位。
Promote it to the world and make it known to everyone.
宣扬天下，使众人皆知。
[The Tomb of General He Liang]
【何梁大将军之墓】
Our He family
我们何家的
The grievances have been redressed.
冤屈已得到平反。
【Astrology Center】
【占星馆】
I am preparing to choose the next owner of Xingxiang Pavilion.
我正准备为星象阁选下一任主人。
Master, we should take our time.
主人，我们应该慢慢来。
There is no need to be so hasty in choosing a successor.
没必要那么急于选择继任者。
We have to prepare for the Astrology Festival
我们得为占星节做准备
And also need to improve our divination tutorial.
并且还需要改进 我们的占卜教程。
We need to recruit new fortune tellers.
我们需要招募新的算命师。
There is a lot to do.
有很多事情要做。
We don't want to rush things.
我们不想仓促行事。
And just like Astrology Day, there’s no need to find someone else to take over.
而且就像占星节一样， 不需要找别人来接手。
others may think
其他人可能会认为
Master has left us.
师父离开了我们。
Yes Master.
是的主人。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
[Xuanzheng Hall]
[Xuanzheng Hall]
Looking south to attack. Nanjiang is in urgent need of help.
寻南袭。 南江急需帮助。
We lost Fanzhou.
我们失去了范州。
All 30,000 soldiers in Wutu City were killed.
五图城三万士兵全部 阵亡。
There are no soldiers of the Chen family guarding the city.
守城的陈家将士已无存。
What did you say. ?
你说什么。？
You are so reckless.
你真是太鲁莽了。
That's not right.
那是不对的。
You are wrong.
您错了。
How could you do this?
你怎么能这样？
What did you say?
你说什么？
How could this happen?
怎么会发生这种事？
Why did Xunnan attack Jialin?
Why did Xunnan attack Jialin?
Senior brother must have been manipulated.
师兄一定是 被人操纵了。
I must find him.
我必须找到他。
Don't be impulsive.
不要冲动。
Even if he is controlled,
即使他被控制，
What can you do yourself?
你自己能做什么？
And if your senior brother really wants to attack Jialin,
而如果你师兄 真想对家霖下手的话
What can you do about this?
你能为这个做什么？
I will lead the troops myself.
我将亲自带兵。
Your Majesty, please don't.
陛下，请不要。
never.
决不。
Your Majesty, you cannot do this.
陛下，您不能这么做。
Your Majesty, please think again.
陛下，请三思。
The royal family is now in decline.
现在的王室已经没落了。
As soon as His Majesty leaves, the family forest will have no roots.
陛下一走， 家林就没有根了。
There will be no one to defend the capital.
京城将无人守城。
It is difficult to avoid the situation of the previous regent.
很难避免 之前摄政王的处境。
Yes, Your Majesty.
是的，陛下。
Your Majesty, please think again.
请陛下三思。
So, who do you think can go to Nanjiang?
那么，你觉得谁能去南江呢？
TT-This…
TT-这个…
Jialin has just calmed down the internal conflicts.
家林刚刚平息了内部矛盾。
Then Xunnan has ulterior motives.
那么寻南是别有用心的。
I cannot protect General Zuo from being destroyed.
我无法保护左将军 不被消灭。
Do I have to look at my right general too?
我也得看我的右将军吗
and thousands of soldiers
和数千名士兵
He died in Nanjiang and could not return to his hometown?
死在南江不能 回故土？
Your Majesty, I have to say something disrespectful.
陛下， 我不得不说一些不敬的话。
Even if you lead the troops yourself, what can you do?
就算你亲自带兵又能做什么？
Our best Jialin commanders have already arrived in Nanjiang.
我们最好的嘉林统帅都 已经到了南江了。
The best men had been exterminated by the regent.
最优秀的人已经 被摄政王消灭了。
If there was no commander like He Liang to lead the troops to kill the enemy,
如果没有何良这样的统帅 带领部队杀敌，
it's no use.
这是没有用的。
I think it's better to send someone to negotiate with Xunnan as soon as possible.
我觉得还是尽快派人去和寻南谈判吧。
Strive to minimize losses at the minimum cost.
力争以最小的成本，将损失降到最低。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
Without commanders like my father and brothers,
如果没有 像我的父亲和兄弟这样的指挥官，
I don't know if I can fight for His Majesty.
我不知道我能否为陛下而战。
TT-This…
TT-这个…
This is ridiculous.
这是荒谬的。
She is just a little commander. How could she take on such responsibility?
她只是一个小指挥官。 她怎么能承担起这样的责任呢？
Apart from,
除了，
She and Ren Yinxiao are friends.
她和任寅晓是朋友。
When they were in Nanjiang, they often communicated with each other.
在南江的时候，他们经常来往。
Who knows if they will...
谁知道他们是否会……
The He family had just been acquitted. How dare you say that?
何家人刚刚被无罪释放。 你怎么敢这么说？
Ren Yinxiao is my senior brother.
任银宵是我的师兄。
this is true.
这是真实的。
All the more reason to avoid suspicion.
这更有理由避免怀疑。
You did contribute to resolving internal conflicts
你确实 为解决内部冲突做出了贡献
But this is a different time.
但这是一个不同的时代。
But I am also from Jia Lin.
但我也是嘉林人。
Protect the people of Jia Lin , defend Jia Lin
保护嘉林人民 ，保卫嘉林
It is the inherent responsibility of the He family.
是何家与生俱来的责任。
I will never forget this.
我永远不会忘记这一点。
Your Majesty, don’t trust people gullibly.
陛下，莫轻信人。
What happened with the Prince Regent should serve as a lesson.
摄政王的事情 应该作为一个教训。
Your Majesty, please think again.
陛下，请三思。
Y'all shut up.
你们都闭嘴。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
If we meet on the battlefield
如果在战场上相遇
Do you really dare to confront Ren Yinxiao?
你真敢跟 任银宵对抗吗？
My sword is always aimed at Jialin's enemies
我的剑永远瞄准家林的敌人
And there will be no mercy.
并且绝不会手下留情。
OK
好的。
I agree with your request for a fight.
我同意你的战斗请求。
You will be the commander of our army.
你将成为我们军队的指挥官。
Come with me to Nanjiang.
跟我去南江吧。
- Your Majesty. No. _ -No!
- 陛下。不 。-不！
Absolutely not! His Majesty!
绝对不！陛下！
Your Majesty, you cannot do this.
陛下，您不能这样做。
Absolutely not!
绝对不！
why not?
为什么不？
He Jiuling risked his life and brought me from the deep palace to this hall.
贺九菱冒着生命危险，将我 从深宫带到了这大殿。
She is more loyal than any of you.
她的忠诚度比你们任何人都高。
Before returning to Beijing, she was the number one general in Nanjiang.
回京之前， 她是南江第一武将。
Every time He Liang marched, she accompanied him.
每次何良行军， 她都陪在他身边。
With every win, her name appears on the report.
每次胜利， 她的名字都会出现在报告中。
If anyone doubts her,
谁要是怀疑她，
Will be regarded as a remnant of the Jiang family.
将会被视为蒋家的余孽。
Your Majesty, there has never been a female commander in history,
陛下， 历史上从未有过女指挥官，
Not to mention fighting alongside the emperor.
更不用说与皇帝并肩作战了。
The master of Xingxiang Pavilion is here.
星象阁的主人来了。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
Your Majesty, it is risky to act rashly at this critical moment .
陛下，在这关键时刻， 轻举妄动是有风险的。
Why not listen to Xingxiang Pavilion’s opinion?
为什么不听听星象阁的意见呢？
Well, that's right.
恩，那就对了。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
The result predicted by Rong Yu is
容宇预测的结果是
This journey is very dangerous. This is extremely ominous.
这次旅程非常危险。 这是极其不祥的。
This this……
这、这……
So, as I said, the best plan right now is
所以，正如我所说，现在最好的计划是
Withdraw troops and negotiate.
撤军并谈判。
but if we don't go
但如果我们不去
The predicted outcome was no chance of survival.
预测的结果是 没有生存的机会。
What should we do? This is a difficult decision.
我们应该做什么？这是一个艰难的决定。
Your Majesty, this...
陛下，这……
This requires further discussion and consideration.
这需要进一步 讨论和考虑。
But it is absolutely impossible for He Jiuling to be the commander-in-chief .
但让贺九龄当统帅， 那是绝对不可能的。
If Xunnan knew about this,
如果寻南知道这件事，
They will laugh at us.
他们会嘲笑我们。
If a woman can do it
如果一个女人能做到
What men can't do
男人做不到的事
Isn't this even more ridiculous for this man?
对于这个男人来说，这不是更可笑吗？
Incompetence is laughable.
无能是可笑的。
Incompetent, stubborn,
无能、固执、
and humiliate a woman
并羞辱一个女人
Ridiculous.
很可笑。
am I wrong?
我错了吗？
you
你们
I have read so many books,
读了那么多书，
But it is not as good as the young master who has not entered the palace.
却还不如未进殿的少爷领悟得好。
After hearing Rong Yu's words, He Jiuling
贺九菱听了容羽的话后，
Do you still dare to go?
你还敢去吗？
certainly.
当然。
OK
好的。
That's perfect.
那很完美。
Then I will let you become the real General He.
那我就让你成为真正的何将军。
This time, it's not you who protects me.
这一次，庇护我的不是你。
But it's me, Xuanyuan Cheng'an,
But it's me, Xuanyuan Cheng'an,
and you, He Jiuling,
and you, He Jiuling,
just like ancestors
就像祖先一样
Xuanyuan, He family,
轩辕、何家，
Sharing life and death with each other.
彼此分享生死。
♫ Under the sunset♫
♫ 黄昏夕阳下♫
♫I have traveled thousands of miles♫
♫我行万里路♫
♫Playing the piano under the moonlight♫
♫月光下弹琴♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 饮料不会让我忘记 ♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫写下对你的思念♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫命运无路可逃♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫回首，我看到你在等待♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河♫
♫You turned around quietly and closed the marriage contract♫
♫你悄悄转身 ，合上婚书♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫问天上有多少颗星星♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫写下对你的思念♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫命运无路可逃♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫回首，我看到你在等待♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河♫
♫I play the piano gently, waiting for passers-by like you♫
♫我轻轻抚琴， 等待着你这样的路人♫
♫It turns out that you are my inseparable destiny♫
♫原来你是我不可分割的宿命♫